<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Octopus Energy</title>
    <description>Octopus Energy is a modern, green energy supplier for the UK.
</description>
    <link>http://tech.octopus.energy/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tech.octopus.energy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 15:19:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello world, would you like to join us?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for super-smart people to join the tech team at Octopus Energy. We’re in the process of designing and building our initial infrastructure. There are many difficult design problems to solve; we need creative, analytical minds who can help tame this notoriously tricky domain.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, our main technologies will be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AWS - using the excellent Hashicorp toolset (Vagrant, Packer, Consul and Terraform).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python - especially Django and Django-REST-Framework. We’re also looking to employ Python’s data processing libraries such as numpy and pandas (although this is still up for debate);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Postgres and DynamoDB&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Memcached and Redis;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React and related modules from the Javascript ecosystem - our consumer-facing user interfaces are going to be super slick;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Node, npm, webpack, babel, gulp etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puppet - for config management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our current priorities lie with server-side work so we’re keen to
speak to Pythonistas, developer data scientists or anyone with a love of automation and data processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’re always interesting in talking to smart, motivated people with an
interest in green tech - we’d love to hear from anyone with experience in the
above. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could this be you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope so. Ideally, you’ll have experience in one or more of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong Python, especially Django and building for the web;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowledge of data processing (eg luigi, pandas, numpy - doesn’t have
to be Python though)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building slick user interfaces with React; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowledge of the modern Javascript ecosystem and asset build pipelines (eg
webpack, mocha, gulp);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-trivial experience with AWS;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experience working with 3rd party APIs, eg XML webservices, REST APIs, FTP
filedrops, that kind of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great opportunity to be an early employee at a revolutionary company. Working at Octopus Energy offers the unique combination of solving difficult technical problems with modern technology as well as working on something that genuinely will make the world a better place (that is, helping transition the UK to a lower carbon future).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of experience isn’t strictly necessary to join. We’re interested in both graduates as well as developers with experience in the above technologies or the UK energy market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this sounds interesting, tell us about yourself via &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&amp;#121;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&amp;#121;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS - Right now, we’re not considering 100% remote candidates. At this early
stage, there’s enormous value in high-bandwidth person-to-person communication
that you can only get by working in the same space. This may change later on of
course.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://tech.octopus.energy/2015/11/23/tech-jobs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tech.octopus.energy/2015/11/23/tech-jobs.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
